Email: manideepcs024@gmail.com

Mob: 9887818001

Site: <a href="https://manideepcs024.github.io/">https://manideepcs024.github.io/</a>

# Manideep Mittal

Senior Associate, Technology

### **Experience summary**

Manideep has 6 years 10 months of experience in the software industry. He has experience in designing web applications in technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, SVG etc. He has experience in Agile based development web based applications. He has successfully worked across static and dynamic mobile responsive websites.

#### Skill set

Programming and scripting languages	HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, SaaS, es6,es5,HTML4,PSD to HTML, JSON, API libraries
Frameworks, tools, and libraries	Angular 1, React Native with redux, React, Knockout, Codelgniter, redux saga
Databases	MySQL
Project management tools	JIRA, Trello
Other tools	SEO (google analytics, indexing), PWA, web optimization.
Production tools	Npm, webpack, gulp, grunt
Version Control	Git (GitHub & bitbucket), SVN

#### Education

• B.tech in Computer Science, RTU, India

## Role in Organization

- 1. Use to create end to end front end application from scratch which involved using a boilerplate and adding NPM / gulp modules etc.
- 2. Going through the shared Mockups and write HTML5/JSX/css3/saas etc and making it a mobile responsive and mobile first web application
- 3. Using libraries and frameworks like bootstrap 4 and previous versions as well, Jquery.
- 4. Data binding through axios, fetch and handling json data storing in local state, local storage etc.
- 5. Managing GWT in cookies, cache.

Email: manideepcs024@gmail.com

Mob: 9887818001

Site: <a href="https://manideepcs024.github.io/">https://manideepcs024.github.io/</a>

- 6. Taking care of SEO with proper alt,h1-h6, meta and other tags
- 7. Taking care of syntax and semantics of entire codebase.
- 8. Using react and redux for writing mobile responsive spa, using libraries like redux thunk and redux saga.
- 9. Creating re-usable smart components, class and functional components.
- 10. UI testing / unit testing cross browser testing, network api call testing, using postmaster and other tools for achieving that.

#### **Professional Experience**

- Currently working with Sapient as Senior Technology Associate L1 from Oct 2019 till date
- Worked with Nagarro as Senior Technology Associate from Jan 2018 till Oct 19
- Worked with CodemyMobile Jaipur from May 2016 to May 2017 as UI Guru
- Worked with Geekshastra as web developer from Sep 2015 to May 2016
- Worked as a freelancer from sep 2014 to sep 2015
- Worked in a service based start up from sep 2013 to sep 2014

## Recent projects

### Admin backend tool

Client	Client was an upcoming start up entrepreneur based in USA
Project overview	<ul> <li>Project involved the development of website for Admin of the product in order to manage information. Information includes adding new data to show end user / customers. Managing users and their roles. Project role was to provide an interface where admin can update / delete any information.</li> <li>Pages containing parts such as login form, sign up form, add, edit, delete of new data.</li> <li>Email subscriptions and contact form filled from end user management.</li> <li>Validating form information.</li> <li>Local storage of logged in user such as token and user details etc.</li> <li>Project involved working on technologies such as angular 1, HTML5, CSS3 etc.</li> </ul>
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Gathered requirement from client and conducted requirement analysis</li> <li>Handled coding and unit testing</li> <li>Worked on Coding standards and code review check lists</li> <li>API Integration</li> </ul>

## Food donating Hybrid app (iOS)

Client	Client is a US based doctor who wants to reduce food waste by providing platform for food donation.
Project overview	Project involved development of iOS app which gives user an opportunity to give away free food or sale to avoid food waste. App includes login / signup with Facebook and email. It has both Google map view and grid layout view for viewing all the available products. App was built in React Native (with redux). Several react native libraries were used such as Google Map, Facebook, Google tracking analysis, notifications permissions etc.
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Built the project from scratch with use of React Native.</li> <li>Worked on coded standards and code review check lists</li> <li>Involved in API integration and unit testing.</li> </ul>

## Mobile responsive website for a IT Company

Client	Client is a leading IT Company delivering software solutions.
Project overview	Project involved development of mobile responsive website which describes portfolio, about us and dozens of other webpages.  Project development included HTML5, CSS3, sass, JS, jQuery, several libraries for sliders, animations, SVG animations, image sprites, CSS animations etc.
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Converting Mock up by to a full active functional webpage</li> <li>Helping understanding designer the need of webpage and designing as per need.</li> <li>Laying down of project architecture i.e. folder structure.</li> <li>Writing code for compiling SaaS to CSS3.</li> <li>Website optimization for fast loading which involved image compression, code minimization etc.</li> <li>Worked on coded standards and code review check lists</li> <li>Involved in API integration and unit testing.</li> </ul>

## Tour and Guide Management website

Client	Client is a US tourist firm which provides guides and tours to tour lovers
Project overview	Project involved development of a Dynamic mobile responsive website which would show list of available guides, tour to tourist.  Project has Login, register forms. Also, admin has access to adding new guides and tours. Also, admin can manage all user and their information.  Project was built on Angular 1, HTML5, and CSS3 etc.
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Built the project after going through given PRD from client.</li> <li>Planning of Project architecture i.e. folder structure, file naming conventions etc.</li> <li>Worked on coded standards and code review check lists</li> <li>Involved in API integration and unit testing.</li> </ul>

Contact:

Email: manideepcs024@gmail.com

Mobile: 9887818001

Site: <a href="http://www.manideepcs024.github.io">http://www.manideepcs024.github.io</a>